

Design Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

### about

As a designer and technologist, I have always been obsessed with discovering how technology may be deployed to deliver an alternative future. As a graduate design researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession through critical theory and a range of ethnographic research techniques that help to resist the internal inertia that new technologies tend assert, and to instead apply user-centered, systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

## education

2016 - 2018

### Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

# SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

# work experience

#### OutVote/COMM!T

2017 Cambridge, MA, USA Founder / UXR / Data Scientist
 Founded civic tech startup COMM!T to test efficacy of peer-enforced smart contracts in driving civic participation.
 Joined forces w/ OutVote civic networking app post-election 2017.

#### **Civic Tech Fellow**

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA UXR / Designer / Engineer
 Developed civic technology for the City of Cambridge, focussing on easy to deploy open source citizen analytics apps and consulting with GoINVO on the MA SNAP application redesign.

### MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA Project Lead / UXR / Engineer
 Managed a democratic capacity
 mapping project for the MIT Community
 Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor
 as well as designed and engineered a
 democratic capacity mapping and
 organizational partnership tool.

#### Fulbright Research Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU Design Research / Project Mgmt
Researched community fablabs at the
Center for Media, Data and Society at
CEU in Budapest. Also piloted OpenLab
public design workshops in UXR,
interface design and hardware/software
prototyping for public projects.

#### SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

#### Data Architect

Full-cycle design and development of a financial-member system handling 25M records, 50 corp. partners, \$5M revenue.